Finding Aid for Donald C. Stewart collection of research materials on Fred Newton Scott, 1980s-1990s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donald C. Stewart collection of research materials on Fred Newton Scott 1980s-1990s
Stewart, Donald C.
5.2 linear feet.
9590 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from Patricia L. Stewart donor no. 8649 in 2000.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Donald C. Stewart was professor of English at Kansas State University.
The Donald C. Stewart collection consists of manuscripts of early drafts of his biography of Fred Newton Scott and collected Newton materials, including correspondence and articles by and about Scott. There are also cassette tape recordings of interviews with individuals who had recollections of Scott.
Subjects:
Stewart, Donald C.; Scott, Fred Newton, 1860-1931.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Stewart, Donald C.; Scott, Fred Newton, 1860-1931.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Rhetoric.; University of Michigan--History.
Contributors: Sound Recordings
Bader, Arno Lehman.; Goodrich, Marion Scott.; Stevens, Albert Kunnen, 1901-1984.; Slusser, Jean Paul, 1886-; Wells, Carlton F. (Carlton Frank), 1898-
Contributors:
Stewart, Patricia L.
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.
- Life and legacy of Fred Newton Scott
  - Manuscript of first draft of published volume, 4 expandable folders (Box 1)
  - Drafts, outlines and notes of published volume (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous project materials (Box 2)
- Research files
  (copies of FNS correspondence, published materials, etc.)
  - Research materials, Vol. I (Box 3)
    (List of materials requested from Bentley Library; record of correspondence with friends, relatives and others who knew FNS; questions to be asked of participants in oral interviews; transcripts of oral interviews)
  - FNS life and career, 1860-1890, Vol. II (Box 3)
  - FNS life and career, 1891-1900, Vol. III (Box 3)
  - FNS life and career, 1900-1905, Vol. IV (Box 3)
  - FNS life and career, 1905-1910, Vol. V, part 1 (Box 3)
  - FNS life and career, 1905-1910, Vol. VI, part 2 (Box 4)
  - FNS life and career, 1911-1915, Vol. VII, part A (Box 4)
  - FNS life and career, 1911-1915, Vol. VII, part B (Box 4)
  - FNS life and career, 1915-1920, Vol. VIII (Box 4)
  - FNS life and career, 1921-1925, Vol. IX (Box 4)
  - FNS life and career, 1925-1927, Vol. X (Box 5)
  - FNS career and departmental matters after his retirement until his death, Vol. XI (Box 5)
  - FNS correspondence, obituaries, post-death materials, notes on children, Vol. XII; now in folder (Box 5)
  - Articles, essays, contributions to literary theory (published and unpublished) by FNS, 1885-1900, Vol. XIII, A; 1 binder and 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Articles, essays, contributions to literary theory (published and unpublished) by FNS, 1900-1915, Vol. XIII, B; 1 binder (Box 5)
  - Articles, essays, contributions to literary theory (published and unpublished) by FNS, 1915-1930, Vol. XIII, C; 1 binder (Box 5)
  - Articles, essays, contributions to literary theory (published and unpublished) by FNS, undated, Vol. XIII, D-1; 1 expandable folder (Box 5)
  - Programs, 1920-1924 teaching materials; tribute to Detroit war dead, Vol. XIII, D-2; 1 expandable folder (Box 5)
- Sound Recordings
  - Interviews with individuals who had recollections of Fred Newton Scott, 9 sound cassettes (Box 6)
    (Interviewees include Arno Bader, Carlton Wells, Jean Paul Slusser, A.K. Stevens, Mrs. Charles Fries, and Marion (Scott) Goodrich)